<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>bootloader on Tuna Cici (Blog)</title>
    <link>https://tunacici.com/blog/tags/bootloader/</link>
    <description>Recent content in bootloader on Tuna Cici (Blog)</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 18 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://tunacici.com/blog/tags/bootloader/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>First-Stage Loaders: BIOS, [U]EFI, iBoot1 &amp; U-Boot (SPL)</title>
      <link>https://tunacici.com/blog/2023/11/first-stage-loaders-bios-uefi-iboot1-u-boot-spl/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tunacici.com/blog/2023/11/first-stage-loaders-bios-uefi-iboot1-u-boot-spl/</guid>
      <description>First-Stage Loaders: BIOS, [U]EFI, iBoot1 &amp;amp; U-Boot (SPL)
Bootloaders, due to their low-level nature, sometimes have to work closely with the hardware. This can lead to some serious constrains, such as having size smaller than 64 KiB or being written in pure machine-code because the stack isn’t properly initialized yet.
This is One Way to Initialize Stack Without A Help From First-Stage Loaders
Naturally, bootloaders are critical as they are literally one of the first programs to run when you press the “Power On” button.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bootloaders &amp; The Wilderness of The Firmware</title>
      <link>https://tunacici.com/blog/2023/10/bootloaders-the-wilderness-of-the-firmware/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tunacici.com/blog/2023/10/bootloaders-the-wilderness-of-the-firmware/</guid>
      <description>Between “pressing the power button” on your device to actually start using it, there exists many pieces of software from different vendors that must execute &amp;amp; work together for a system to Gracefully Boot™.
Most modern devices are capable of booting in a few seconds &amp;amp; being fully ready to be used. There are even areas (safety-critical) where sub 1 second boot time is not only possible but required! These timings are fascinating when you learn how much “software switching” happens &amp;amp; the important role they each play.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
