<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Architecture on Tuna Cici (Blog)</title>
    <link>https://tunacici.com/blog/tags/architecture/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Architecture on Tuna Cici (Blog)</description>
    <generator>Hugo 0.125.0</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://tunacici.com/blog/tags/architecture/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>seL4 Microkernel: Architecture</title>
      <link>https://tunacici.com/blog/2024/10/sel4-microkernel-architecture/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tunacici.com/blog/2024/10/sel4-microkernel-architecture/</guid>
      <description>The balance between safety and security versus high-performance and high-throughput has always been a challenge in OS design. Although not mutually exclusive, making something safer usually lowers performance, which could be due to software design or hardware limitations.&#xA;To combat this, modern hardware features things like MMUs, privilege levels and virtualization. But they alone are not enough. The software should also be designed and implemented smartly to make use of the hardware the right way.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What are CPU Architectures &amp; ISAs? ELI5</title>
      <link>https://tunacici.com/blog/2022/10/what-are-cpu-architectures-isas-eli5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tunacici.com/blog/2022/10/what-are-cpu-architectures-isas-eli5/</guid>
      <description>We all probably have heard them: ARM, RISC-V, CISC, x86, x64, AARCH64, AMD64… Why are there so many of them? Why do they sound so mathematical and scientific? And most importantly What do they even mean?&#xA;Here in this article I will try to clear the confessions about all the terms above. I will talk about CPUs, CPU architectures and instruction sets. At the end, you will have the fundamental understanding of their meaning and their place in this big tech world.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
