<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>linux on tunacici</title>
    <link>https://tunacici.com/blog/tags/linux/</link>
    <description>Recent content in linux on tunacici</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 05 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://tunacici.com/blog/tags/linux/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>GNU/Linux CLI Shells ELI5: sh, bash, zsh and more</title>
      <link>https://tunacici.com/blog/2023/04/gnu/linux-cli-shells-eli5-sh-bash-zsh-and-more/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tunacici.com/blog/2023/04/gnu/linux-cli-shells-eli5-sh-bash-zsh-and-more/</guid>
      <description>If you’ve ever interacted with a GNU/Linux system, chances are you’ve heard about shells like sh, bash and zsh. But what are these shells, why are they so important? What even is a shell? And “most importantly” why should you even care about them?
In this article, we’ll take a closer look at GNU/Linux shells and try to explain them in an ELI5-fashioned way. We’ll discuss some essential terms like: terminal, shell and CLI.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Linux Networking ELI5 — Part 4, Minecraft &amp; Web Server</title>
      <link>https://tunacici.com/blog/2023/02/linux-networking-eli5-part-4-minecraft-web-server/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tunacici.com/blog/2023/02/linux-networking-eli5-part-4-minecraft-web-server/</guid>
      <description>Hello and welcome to the final part of this ELI5 series. So far, we have learned the fundamentals of computer networking through questions like ‘what is networking?’, ‘what is the TCP/IP model?’ and ‘what are ports?’. We have covered most of the important networking terms, but there are still A LOT MORE things out there. However, let’s just leave them for future articles:)
In this final part we will not be explaining new networking terms, but instead we will use them to build something!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Linux Networking ELI5 — Part 3, Ports, TCP/IP &amp; Firewalls</title>
      <link>https://tunacici.com/blog/2023/01/linux-networking-eli5-part-3-ports-tcp/ip-firewalls/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tunacici.com/blog/2023/01/linux-networking-eli5-part-3-ports-tcp/ip-firewalls/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to the part 3 of my Linux Networking ELI5 series! In the previous article, we have talked about IP addresses, the idea behind the NAT and DHCP servers.
Today’s stars are TCP/IP model, ports and firewalls. We will try to answer what they are, how do they work and how to use them in our Linux machines. Unlike the previous articles, this one will be more software centric. Meaning, there will be many terminal commands and practical examples.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Linux Networking ELI5 — Part 2, IP, NAT &amp; DHCP</title>
      <link>https://tunacici.com/blog/2023/01/linux-networking-eli5-part-2-ip-nat-dhcp/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tunacici.com/blog/2023/01/linux-networking-eli5-part-2-ip-nat-dhcp/</guid>
      <description>Hey everyone! In this article we are continuing our Linux Networking journey from where we left off. Previously, we made a simple introduction to networks, interfaces and basic Linux commands. Now, here in this article we will go deeper into the networking itself and talk about IP addresses, NAT, DHCP and more.
If you haven’t read the Part-1, I highly encourage you to give it a quick look. Most of the stuff here will make a lot more sense if you know about networks and interfaces.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Linux Networking ELI5 — Part 1, Networks &amp; Interfaces</title>
      <link>https://tunacici.com/blog/2023/01/linux-networking-eli5-part-1-networks-interfaces/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tunacici.com/blog/2023/01/linux-networking-eli5-part-1-networks-interfaces/</guid>
      <description>As we all know, Linux is a very powerful operating system. Even if it’s not as popular as Windows or macOS, it’s importance and power is no joke. Heck, it might even be the most important OS ever (depending on the person you ask) and there is a good justification for that.
Daily Time Spent Online — Source: oberlo.com
Look at the visualized data above. You can clearly see that we spent a lot of time on the internet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Linux Filesystem Explained</title>
      <link>https://tunacici.com/blog/2022/11/linux-filesystem-explained/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tunacici.com/blog/2022/11/linux-filesystem-explained/</guid>
      <description>If you have ever used a Linux system, you probably heard the term root filesystem. When you install something with apt or want to configure an application’s settings, you need to meddle with the root filesystem. And if you are a developer deploying an application to Linux, just know that you need to get your hands dirty with it. But what is the root filesystem, anyway?
In this article I will explain the root filesystem, it’s brief history and all the directories inside it.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
