<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>home automation on joonas.fi</title>
    <link>https://joonas.fi/tags/home-automation/</link>
    <description>Recent content in home automation on joonas.fi</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 Aug 2020 08:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://joonas.fi/tags/home-automation/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Displaying RSS feed with Home Assistant</title>
      <link>https://joonas.fi/2020/08/displaying-rss-feed-with-home-assistant/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Aug 2020 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joonas.fi/2020/08/displaying-rss-feed-with-home-assistant/</guid>
      <description>I wanted to display news in my Home Assistant dashboard.
Home Assistant has &amp;ldquo;Feedreader&amp;rdquo; integration which supports getting data from an RSS feed into HA&amp;rsquo;s event bus, but it doesn&amp;rsquo;t mention a way of displaying the entries (or storing them as sensor attributes that would be accessible from UI).
There&amp;rsquo;s 3rd party integration and an UI component to do the job, but I wanted to do this with as close to vanilla Home Assistant as possible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Home automation ideas &amp; my setup</title>
      <link>https://joonas.fi/2020/01/19/home-automation-ideas-and-my-setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2020 10:50:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joonas.fi/2020/01/19/home-automation-ideas-and-my-setup/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve got so many good automation ideas from other people, so it&amp;rsquo;s fair that I pay it forward by listing my own automations so other people can get ideas! I also describe my setup, gear and my no-cloud policy etc.
My automations A lazy dump of my automations:
When nobody&amp;rsquo;s home and I open the apartment door (door/window sensor) and it&amp;rsquo;s dark, a hallway light turns on.
When the last person leaves the apartment, there&amp;rsquo;s a button next to the apartment door that makes all the lights/devices turn off.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IKEA Trådfri bulbs without Trådfri gateway: getting started (complete instructions)</title>
      <link>https://joonas.fi/2018/12/17/ikea-tradfri-bulbs-without-tradfri-gateway-getting-started/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Dec 2018 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joonas.fi/2018/12/17/ikea-tradfri-bulbs-without-tradfri-gateway-getting-started/</guid>
      <description>TL;DR; control all Zigbee devices (Philips Hue, Xiaomi smarthome, IKEA Trådfri etc etc.) more securely, more cheaply, more creatively, more robustly, more privately and be in total control!
You still need some hardware to interface with Zigbee, but using something like Texas Instruments&amp;rsquo; CC2531 brings a lot of benefits. More on this very closely below!
Why &amp;amp; overview Why would I want a custom Zigbee gateway? Well, it brings us these benefits:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
